Welcome to our training on how to move your FTL shipments with Amazon Freight.
Do
you have full truckload or FTL shipments to move?
You can take advantage of Amazon's
advanced technology and network of over 30,000 Amazon-owned trailers and trusted
carriers to move your shipments inbound to Amazon, to your facilities and to
third-party facilities all with Amazon Freight.
This training will cover benefits
of Amazon Freight and how to book and track your shipments.
Amazon Freight offers a
variety of benefits to help ensure your shipment experience is simple and
reliable from start to finish.
Amazon Freight provides shippers with 24/7
network monitoring and customer support, GPS tracking and easy online payments.
You'll have access to competitive and transparent spot rates or the option to
secure contract rates on your most used lanes.
You can access your instant quote
directly on the Amazon Freight website.
All you need to provide is your shipment's
pickup city or zip code, delivery city or zip code and pickup date.
To start
booking shipments with Amazon Freight, you'll first create a shipper account.
Once
your account is created, you'll have immediate access to a spending limit so
you can start booking right away.
Now let's cover how to book with Amazon Freight
starting with shipments inbound to Amazon.
To book a fulfillment by Amazon or
FBA shipment inbound to Amazon, you'll first create an FBA shipment in Seller
Central.
On step four of the send to Amazon workflow, confirm carrier and
pallet information and then select non-partnered carrier and other from the
carrier drop-down.
Once your FBA shipment is created, visit the Amazon Freight
portal to book and schedule a pickup date for the load.
To do this, visit the
shipments page and select new quote.
On the get quote page, specify that your
shipment is going to an Amazon facility and provide both pickup and delivery
location information.
In the delivery location field, provide the Amazon
facility code for your FBA shipment.
Then select a requested pickup date for
your load.
This date will be confirmed based on delivery appointment
availability once your booking is complete.
Next, confirm your location
details.
On the book shipment page, provide your shipment details.
In the
purchase orders field, provide your Amazon reference ID from the FBA shipment
created in Seller Central.
Once all your information is entered, you're ready to
book your shipment.
You'll be directed to your confirmation page where you can
download your shipment's bill of lading or BOL.
You'll also receive an email
confirming your shipment pickup date and time.
For booking shipments outside of
Amazon, like to your facility or a third-party facility, visit the shipments page
and select new quote.
On the get quote page, specify that your shipment isn't
going to an Amazon facility and provide pickup and delivery location details and
a pickup date.
Once complete, click save and continue.
Next, confirm your location
details.
On the book shipment page, input your shipment details.
Once all
information is entered, you can now book your shipment.
You'll be directed to
your shipment's confirmation page where you can download your BOL.
Once your
shipment is picked up, the view shipment details page will provide tracking
information for your shipment.
Amazon owned trailers and trusted carriers are
equipped with GPS so you can have full visibility of your shipments from pickup
to delivery.
For more information or to start booking, visit the Amazon Freight
website.
This concludes our training on how to move your FTL shipments with
Amazon Freight.
You now have the tools to move your shipments using Amazon's
network and technology.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store!